Schaefer, Vincent; Papers ua902.010
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Munitalp Foundation, 1940-1968; Undated; 3; 11.5 cubic ft.
  - Correspondence, 1950-1965; Undated; 3.3
    The letters include letters directed to him alone, letters that colleagues sent to one another but also carbon copied to Schaefer, and carbon copies of correspondence that Schaefer sent out. Most of these files came to the archives bundled together without labels or other identification, while some were singled out by specific people or topics. The archivist kept that arrangement, so researchers will find most of the letters filed under the name "general" and identified by year. Others are titled by a particular person's name or subject as well as the year. All of the correspondence is arranged chronologically.
    - Africa, 1957-1959 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 1)
    - American Polar Bear Expedition- Paul Seydel, 1955 May 27 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 2)
    - Aspliden, Carl- Travel, 1957-1959 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 3)
    - Cooperative Research- Weather Control, 1954-1957 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 4)
    - Draft of Letter to Malin and Connie Sorsbie- Final Communication, 1964 February 14 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 5)
    - Educational Program, 1957-1958 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 6)
    - Evaporation Studies, 1954-1958 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 7)
    - Falconer, Raymond- Correspondence with Occasional Data, 1954-1958 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 8)
    - Flower, Jr. Luie C. - Minatare, Nebraska, 1956 July 05; 1956 July 31 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 9)
    - General, 1950 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 10)
    - General, 1951 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 11)
    - General, 1952 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 12-13)
    - General, 1953 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 14-16)
    - General, 1954 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 17-22)
    - General, 1955 (Box 10 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 23-26)
    - General, 1955 (Box 11 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 1-4)
    - General, 1956 (Box 11 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 5-11)
    - General, 1957 (Box 11 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 12-17)
    - General, 1958 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 1-7)
    - General, 1959 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 8-10)
    - General, 1960 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 11)
    - General, 1961 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 12)
    - General, 1962 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 13)
    - General, 1963 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 14)
    - General, 1964 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 15)
    - General, 1965 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 16)
    - General, Undated (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 17)
    - Greenland, 1953-1954 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 18)
    - Harney, Pat- Cameras and Reel Films, 1958 February 03; Undated (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 19)
    - Invitations/Reservations, 1957 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 20)
    - Lois Schaefer to Vincent During Trip to Africa, 1957 October; Undated (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 21)
    - MacCready, Paul, 1954-1958 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 22)
    - Martimer, W.A., 1958 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 23)
    - Mount Washington Observatory, 1955 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 24)
    - Mount Washington Observatory, 1956 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 25)
    - Mount Washington Observatory, 1957-1959 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 26)
    - Mount Washington Observatory, 1960-1961 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 27)
    - Museum at the Atmosphere, 1957-1959 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 28-31)
    - National Science Foundation, 1955-1958 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 32)
    - Office of Naval Research, 1953-1959 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 33)
    - Other Weather Professionals, 1959 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 34)
    - Personnel and Reports, 1953-1958 (Box 12 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 35)
  - Subject Files, 1948-1968; Undated; 3.4
    The subject files feature a variety of materials that supplement Schaefer's Munitalp research documents, such as ephemera from some of his many travels, conference brochures, and weather research activities of groups not affiliated with Munitalp. This subseries also includes administrative files such as personnel information, grant writing endeavors, and budgeting, which are reflections of Schaefer's role as director of research. There are also photographs of Schaefer and colleagues, non-Skyfire research projects, travels in and out of the United States, and more generic subjects such as research equipment.
    - Accounts and Expenses, 1953-1959 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 1)
    - Activities, 1952-1956 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 2)
    - Adirondack Conference on Atmospheric Nuclei, 1957-1958 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 3)
    - Adirondack Conference on Atmosphere, Second, 1958-1959 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 4-5)
    - Africa Administration, 1958-1959 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 6)
    - Africa-Postcards (unwritten), Undated (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 7)
    - Africa Trip (fragment), 1957 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 8)
    - Africa Trip: Memo and Proposed Itinerary, 1957 August 06 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 9)
    - Agriculture in the West, 1953 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 10)
    - Albertus Magnus Guild, 1955 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 11)
    - American Meteorological Society, 1954-1958 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 12-14)
    - American Meteorological Society 120th National Meeting- Photo, 1953 January 26 (Oversized 2, Folder 14)
    - American Meteorological Society: Award for Outstanding Services to the Advance of Meteorology by a Corporation, 1953 January (Oversized 2, Folder 15)
    - American Meteorological Society Meeting, NYU- Photo, 1955 January 26 (Oversized 2, Folder 16)
    - Arid Lands, 1953-1955 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 15)
    - Biological and Chemical Defense Planning Board, 1960 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 16)
    - "Brief Outline of Atmospheric Research Activities underway by Various Organizations in the United States", 1958 November 10 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 17)
    - Business Summaries Notebook, 1953 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 18)
    - Canadian Meteorological Service, 1954 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 19)
    - Central Park Observatory, 1957 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 20)
    - Climatic Relations, 1953-1955 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 21)
    - Cloud Modification Photos and Written Materials- Background for Atmosphere Chapter 8, 1948-1968 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 22)
    - Conference on the Evaluation of Weather Modification, 1954 September 22-1954 September 24 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 23)
    - Contracts, 1953-1954 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 24)
    - Daily Olympian: "The Sandy Point Weather Project", 1954 (Oversized 2, Folder 17)
    - Denver- Water Needs, ca. 1955 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 25)
    - European Trip, Notes on, 1954 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 26)
    - Federation of American Scientists Newsletter, 1959 February 10 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 27)
    - File Systems, 1956-1960 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 28)
    - Fortune Magazine- "Forecast for Weather Control: Brighter," Francis Bello, 1958 May (Oversized 9)
    - General Policy, 1956 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 29)
    - Geodesy and Geophysics, International Union, 1953-1955 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 30)
    - Gisborne, H.T.- Obituary, Undated (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 31)
    - Glaciology on Mount Kenya (IGY), News Clippings, 1957-1958 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 32)
    - Grants, 1953-1959 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 33-35)
    - Guest Book: Munitalp Offices, New York City, 1954-1960 (Oversized 9)
    - Hawaii Institute of Geophysics, 1958 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 36)
    - Jeppesen R Co, Air Map of United Airlines, Denver, Colorado, 1956 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 37)
    - Job Applicants, 1954-1958 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 38)
    - Johnston, Albert Wheeler- Obituaries- Founder of Munitalp, 1952 August 25; Undated (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 39)
    - Long Range Weather Forecasting Conference- List of Participants, 1958 September (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 40)
    - Johnston, Albert, 1951 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 41)
    - Mailing Lists and Miscellaneous, 1954-1958 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 42)
    - Meeting at Princeton Inn- Photos of Schaefer, Unidentified Colleagues, Undated (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 43)
    - Microcards, 1955-1956 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 44)
    - Morro Bay Stack, Photo, 1956 January 23 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 45)
    - Northwest United States Photo Slides, 1948-1953 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 46)
    - Notebook- M.I.T. Faculty Club, Undated (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 47)
    - Photos, Miscellaneous, Undated (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 48-49)
    - "Proceedings: First Forum of the Munitalp Foundation, Inc." Includes Cover Letter from Vernon Crudge, 1951 November 14; 1952 January 28 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 50)
    - Rossby, Carl-Gustaf, 1955-1957 (Box 13 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 51)
    - Photos for Publication, 1953-1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 1)
    - Photos Loaned and Returned, 1959-1967 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 2-3)
    - Plans for Africa Trip, 1957 October (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 4)
    - Precipitation Physics, 1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 5)
    - Priest River and Various Meteorology Meetings, 1953-1954 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 6)
    - Project Skyfire and Jetstream Work, 1955 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 7)
    - Public Relations, 1956-1957 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 8)
    - Physical Science Study Committee/Laura Fermi- with Manuscripts Relating to "Monograph on Weather", 1958 May 02; Undated (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 9)
    - Rensselaer Alumni News, 1959 March (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 10)
    - Reprint Requests, 1953-1961 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 11-14)
    - Royal Meteorological Society- Meeting Announcements and Meeting Notes, 1948-1950 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 15)
    - Scandinavian-American Meteorological Meeting- Script for Talk on Lyse Monastery, 1958 June 24 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 16)
    - Schaefer and Malin Sorsbie, Dispute Over Policy/Procedures in Africa vs. United States, 1958 September 11; 1958 December 13 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 17)
    - Schaefer, Vincent Taking Pictures out of Window of Plane, Photo, 1955 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 18)
    - Schaefer, Vincent, Photos, 1956; Undated (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 19)
    - Schenectady-Photo Negatives- Album for Princess Beatrix of the Netherlands, 1959 September 11 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 20)
    - Scientific Adventure Kits, 1957 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 21)
    - Science Forum, Photo, 1953 December 30 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 22)
    - Security, 1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 23)
    - Ship Code Card- U.S. Department of Commerce Weather Bureau, Undated (Oversized 4, Folder 15)
    - Skyfire Lookouts- Paul MacCready, Jr., 1954 March 29 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 24)
    - Slo-Mo-Shun V, Seattle, Photograph, Undated (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 25)
    - Snow Committee, 1954-1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 26)
    - Snow-Preparations for Film, 1958 November 25 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 27)
    - Snow Survey Bulletins, 1953-1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 28)
    - Solar-Terrestrial Research, Institute for, 1960 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 29)
    - Sorsbie, Malin, 1957-1959; 1984 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 30-31)
    - State Museum Advisory Council, 1956 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 32)
    - Surface Chemistry, 1954-1956 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 33)
    - Television Program, 1954-1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 34)
    - Time Lapse Cloud Films, 1954 November 04; 1957 October 25 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 35)
    - Time Lapse Films, Northern Rocky Mountain Experiment Station, Project Black Sheep, Cloud Seeding, 1952-1953 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 36)
    - Tornadoes and Tornado Institute, 1954-1955 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 37)
    - Travel Ephemera- Africa, Germany, England, 1957; Undated (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 38)
    - Trips, 1954-1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 39-43)
    - United Nations University, 1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 44)
    - Universitätsinstitut für Meteirikigie and Geophysik, 1954 February 03; 1954 March 27 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 45)
    - University of Missouri, Columbia, 1954 October 15-1955 April 05 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 46)
    - U.S. Forest Service Brochure-Fire Control Notes, 1952 July (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 47)
    - Vincent and Lois Schaefer with Unidentified Persons, 1950s (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 48)
    - Wadati, Dr. Kiyoo- Japanese Central Meteorological Observatory, 1954 June-1954 October (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 49)
    - Weather Control: Adirondack Conference, 1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 50)
    - Weather Control: Advisory Committee on Weather Control, 1953-1958 (Box 14 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 51)
    - Weather Control: Advisory Committee on Weather Control, 1953-1958 (Box 15 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 1-2)
    - Weather Forecasting Competitions, 1955-1956 (Box 15 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 3)
    - Weather Inc. Photo Negatives, Undated (Box 15 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 4)
    - Weather-Related News Clippings, 1955-1957; Undated (Box 15 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 5)
    - Weather-Related Photo Negatives, 1958; 1961; Undated (Box 15 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 6)
  - Reports & Publications, 1952-1960; Undated; 3.5
    This subseries is devoted entirely to articles and reports from Schaefer's Munitalp years. Materials cover a range of topics including Project Skyfire, jet stream studies, cloud seeding, particle studies, and research on the relationship between environmental factors and the weather. Since this subseries is comparatively smaller than the reports and publications for General Electric, works by Schaefer and others are mixed together. The files are arranged chronologically, then alphabetically by article/report title if necessary. Folder titles note the author of each work. For Schaefer's writings, the archivist noted if there is a manuscript included with the published copy.
    - "A Proposed Program for the Munitalp Foundation," V.J. Schaefer, Manuscript Only, ca. 1952 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 1)
    - Occasional Papers (0001-0010), 1952 October-1955 April (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 2)
    - "Twinkle of Stars May Show Jet Streams of Wind," Wadsworth Likely, 1953 February 10 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 3)
    - "The Munitalp Atmospheric Research Project," V.J. Schaefer, 1953 May 25 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 4)
    - "Cloud Photography Project," V.J. Schaefer, Occasional Paper #2, 1953 June (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 5)
    - "The Use of Clouds for Locating the Jet stream," V.J. Schaefer, 1953 October 30 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 6)
    - Jet Stream Articles (2) by Captain Bernard C. Frost, 1953 December; Undated (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 7)
    - "Cloud Forms of the Jet Stream," V.J. Schaefer, 1953 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 8)
    - "Cloud Photography," V.J. Schaefer, 1953 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 9)
    - "Flying in Jet Stream Winds,"Shell Aviation News, Manuscript, 1953 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 10)
    - Cal Tech Report to Munitalp- Oxygen Isotope, Paul MacCready, Jr., 1954 March 29 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 11)
    - "Atmospheric Electricity Associated with Jet Streams," V.J. Schaefer, Manuscript, ca. May 1954 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 12)
    - "New Frontiers in the Sky," V.J. Schaefer, WGY Science Forum, 1954 May 05 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 13)
    - "A Possible Explanation of Explosions and Fires Caused by the Electrification of Fine Particle Sprays," V.J. Schaefer, Manuscript Only, 1954 June 07 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 14)
    - "A Possible Relationship Between the Solar Corona and Weather Conditions in the Central Midwest," E.D. Farthing, 1954 September 22 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 15)
    - "Cloud and Atmospheric- Electric Observations of the Formative Stages of Worcester, Massachusetts Tornado," R. Falconer and V.J. Schaefer, 1954 November (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 16)
    - "Project Skyfire: A Progress Report on Lightning Fire and Atmospheric Research" by J.S. Barros, V.J. Schaefer and P.B. Macready Jr., 1954 November (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 17)
    - Review of U. Nakaya's Book Snow Crystals-Natural and Artificial, V.J. Schaefer, with letter, 1954 December 08 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 18)
    - "A Case Study of Jet Stream Clouds," V.J. Schaefer and W.E. Hubert, Occasional Paper #11, with manuscript, 1954 December (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 19)
    - Occasional Papers (0001-0010), 1954 December-1956 July (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 20)
    - "Report of Activities During Field Trip to Hawaiian Islands October 24-November 24, 1954, V.J. Schaefer, ca. 1954 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 21)
    - "Jet Streams and Project Skyfire," V.J. Schaefer, with Manuscript, 1955 January (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 22)
    - "High and Low Elevations as Thermal Source Regions", MacCready, Paul B. Jr., 1955 February (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 23)
    - "Thunderstorms and Project Skyfire," V.J. Schaefer, with Manuscript, 1955 April (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 24)
    - "Artificially Induced Precipitation and its Potentialities," V.J. Schaefer, 1955 June (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 25)
    - "Nuclei, Water Drops, and Ice Crystals II," V.J. Schaefer, with Manuscript, 1955 June (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 26)
    - "Report of Activities During Lecture and Field Trip to Southwest," V.J. Schaefer, Manuscript, April 20-May 6, 1955, ca. June 1955 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 27)
    - "Artificial Snowfall from Mountain Clouds," Ludlam, F.H., 1955 August (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 28)
    - Occasional Papers (0021-0042), 1955 August-1958 June (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 29)
    - "Utilizing a Daily Computed Index of Solar Coronal Activity as the Solar Parameter," E.D. Forthing, 1955 September 15 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 30)
    - "Question of Meteoric Dust in the Atmosphere," V.J. Schaefer, with Manuscript, 1955 September (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 31)
    - "Atmospheric Electricity Associated with Jet Streams," V.J. Schaefer, 1955 November (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 32)
    - "Mohawks in the Lower Valley," V.J. Schaefer, Manuscript only, 1955 November (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 33)
    - "Adventures in Meteorology," V.J. Schaefer, 1955 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 34-36)
    - "The Geography of the Air," S.T. Possony and L. Rosenzweig, 1955 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 37)
    - "Jet Streams and Project Skyfire," V.J. Schaefer, with Manuscript, 1955 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 38)
    - Man's Role in Changing the Face of the Earth, Articles, 1955 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 39)
    - "Meteorology," Malkus, Joanne Starr, 1955 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 40)
    - "Report of Activities During Lecture and Field Trip to Southwest," V.J. Schaefer, 1955 April 20-1955 May 06 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 41)
    - "Report on Work Done During 1955 in Developing an Objective Long-Range Weather Forecast Method," Manuscript, Falconer, Raymond (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 42)
    - "Science Improves Jet-Stream Navigation," Hawkes, Russell, 1956 April 02 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 43)
    - "On the Maintenance of Trade Winds," J.S. Malkus, 1956 April 16 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 44)
    - "Second Report on Cloud-Seeding Over Sun Moon Lake Area" (Taiwan Rain Stimulation Institute), 1956 April (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 45)
    - "On the Atmosphere Circulation at 500 MB in the Auroral Belt," Riehl, Herbert, 1956 May (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 46)
    - "The Forms of Ice Clouds: II," Ludlam, F.H., 1956 July (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 47)
    - "Simple Experiments on Atmospheric Physics VII- Production of A Diamond Dust Shower," V.J. Schaefer, 1956 December (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 49)
    - "Atmospheric Electrical Measurements in the Hawaiian Islands," V.J. Schaefer, Manuscript included, 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 50-51)
    - "Atmospheric Studies from a Moving Weather Observatory," V.J. Schaefer, et al., 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 52)
    - "Jet Streams," Lee, R., 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 53)
    - "A Mobile Atmospheric Research Laboratory" (US Forest Service), Manuscript, Fuquay, D.M., 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 54)
    - "The Skyfire Cloud Survey," Barrows, J.S., 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 55)
    - "Some Relationships of Experimental Meteorology to Arid Land Water Sources" Occasional Paper #18, V.J. Schaefer, 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 56)
    - "Stereo Cloud Photography Equipment," MacCready, Paul B. Jr., 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 57)
    - "Suggestions for Continued Flight Research for Tornado Study," V.J. Schaefer, 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 58)
    - "Thunderstorm Analysis in the Northern Rocky Mountains," Coulson, Dever, 1956 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 59)
    - "Recommendations for a National Institute for Atmospheric Research," V.J. Schaefer and B. Vonnegut, 1957 January (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 60)
    - "Atmospheric Studies from a Moving weather Observatory," V.J. Schaefer, 1957 March (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 61)
    - "Noctilucent Clouds," Ludlam, F.H., 1957 March (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 62)
    - "New Ideas on Hail, Thunder, and Tropical Storms," Ludlam, F.H., 1957 April (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 63)
    - "Weather Reconnaissance by Airborne Trime Lapse Camera," V.J. Schaefer and WM Taylor, with Manuscript, 1957 April; Undated (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 64)
    - "When is Human Behavior Predetermined?" Boring, E.G., 1957 April (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 65)
    - "The San Francisco Peaks: A Unique Region for Atmospheric Research," V.J. Schaefer, Manuscript, 1957 May 29 (Box 16 (3-Munitalp Foundation), Folder 66)